Guide to the Ernie O'Malley Papers AIA.060
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VIII. Nationalistic Material, 1643-1966, undated
  - "The Duty of the Hour" by Darrell Figgis from The Sinn Fein Cathecism (Messrs. Whelan and Son, Ormond Quay), circa 1920 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Eire: The Irish Nation partial issues - April 7, April 21, July 7, 1923; September 6, 1924, 1923-1924 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Erskine Childers" booklet by Frank Gallagher (Leslie Smith and Co., London), undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - "Heads Up" flier (Ernie O'Malley writing on verso), Jun 28, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - "Irish Leaders of our time" pamphlet series (An Cosantoir, Dublin), nos. 10-14, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - The Irish Review Vol. 1, No. 5 (signed by Ernie O'Malley in jail), Dec 23, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - "Is Ireland a Danger to England?: The Strategic Question Examined" (reprinted from The Irish Bulletin, London, July 21, 1929), undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - "A Letter from the Earl of Westmoreland British Viceroy to Ireland to William Pitt, Prime Minister of England" (published byBen Franklin Bureau, Chicago; issued by American Association for the Recognition of the Republic of Ireland), Jan 18, 1792 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - "Letter of the Supreme Council of the Confederate Catholics to the Mayor of Kilkenny, 22 Sept 1643" lithographed reprint, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Local Security Force: Organisation, Function and Duties of the Local Security Force" pamphlet, undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - "National Assocation of Old I.R.A." appeal for funds, circa 1930s (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - "The National Situation" inaugural Sinn Fein address by J.J. O'Kelly(Sinn Fein Standing Committee), Oct 1936 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - "The Orange Card" booklet (All-Party Anti-Partition Conference, Dublin), circa 1949 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Poblacht na hEireann War News No. 106 [Dublin?], Dec 2, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Poblacht na hEireann The Republic of Ireland Vol 1. nos 22-27, May 25, 1922-Jun 29, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Postscript" by Philip Noel-Baker, Parliamentary Secretary to the Minister of War Transport, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - "Proclamation: Offer of Amnesty" (Gen. Richard Mulcahy), Feb 8, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "Saorstat Eireann: Censorship of Publications Act, 1929; Register of Prohibited Publications as on the 30th Sept 1935" booklet (Stationery Office, Dublin), circa 1935 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - "The Republic of Ireland Addresses His Holiness the Pope (Sinn Fein Standing Committee), Dec 16, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - "Republicans Stop Talking! Neutrals Shut Up! Spies and Informers Beware!" (flier during Irish Civil War), circa 1922-1923 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - "Robert Emmet's Speech from the Dock, 1803" booklet (Irish Book Bureau, Dublin), undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - "Sean McCaughey - The Truth" pamphlet (Republican Prisoners' Release Association, Dublin), circa 1940-1950 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - "Sinn Fein Courts in Operation" article by W.H. Brayden, in Journal of the American Bar Association, Sep 1920 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Saoirse na hEireann, Irish Freedom: clippings, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - War News No. 5 Jul 1, 19__, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Weekly News Bulletin: clippings (from Friends of Irish Freedom, New York), Oct 1921 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings: "Dublin Castle Secrets," Weekly Freeman, Nov 22, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings: The Evening Telegraph (Dublin), Apr 1, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Newspaper Clippings: fragments, 1921-1922 (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Series IX. Jack B. Yeats, 1904-1980
  The series contains correspondence, articles, clippings, invitations, cancelled checks, receipts, notes, exhibition catalogs, stamps and photographs collected by Ernie O'Malley relating to Jack B. Yeats, as well as, items relating to Yeats' father, John B. Yeats, and brother, William Butler Yeats. Items in this series are of both a personal and professional nature. O'Malley and Jack B. Yeats met in Ireland during the 1930s and developed a friendship that lasted until their deaths in 1957. In addition to being a patron of Yeats' artwork, O'Malley served on the Jack B. Yeats National Loan Exhibition Committee and authored the introduction for the exhibition's catalog in 1945. Throughout the course of their friendship Yeats gifted O'Malley various pencil sketches and writings by John B. Yeats, in addition to several letters written by the elder Yeats to his other son, William Butler Yeats. Other items include Yeats materials collected by Ernie O'Malley's son, Cormac O'Malley.
  - Index to Jack B. Yeats material, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Article: "Fifty Years of Irish Painting" Thomas MacGreevy in The Capuchin Annual, undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Article: "Jack B. Yeats: An Impression" by Mairin Allen, undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Article "The Yeats Exhibition" C.P. Curran in The Capuchin Annual, undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Article: "Three Historical Paintings by Jack B. Yeats" Thomas MacGreevy in The Capuchin Annual, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Article: "Visits to Jack Yeats" John Rothenstein in New English Review, Jul 1946 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Commemorative Stamps: Jack B. Yeats (on postcard addressed to COM), 1971 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - "The Connaught Toast" Cuala Press card; EOM correspondence on verso, undated (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence: Yeats, Jack B. to EOM, 1939-1951; cuid36770 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence: Yeats, John B. to William Butler Yeats (Willie), 1916-1919; cuid36771 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Envelope - addressed to EOM with Jack B. Yeats insignia, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Exhibition of Later Paintings by Jack B. Yeats" Victor Waddington Galleries, Dublin, Nov 1943 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Jack Yeats: Irish Expressionist" Birmingham Museum of Art, Birmingham, Alabama, Mar 15, 1980-Apr 30, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Jack B. Yeats: National Loan Exhibition" National College of Art, Dublin, Jun 1945-Jul 1945 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Later Paintings by Jack B Yeats" at the Victor Waddington Galleries, Dublin (annotations and signature of EOM), Mar 1945 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Pictures by Anne Yeats" annotated, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Paintings by Jack B. Yeats" Victor Waddington Galleries, Dublin, Mar 1945 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Paintings by Jack B. Yeats" Victor Waddington Galleries, Dublin, Oct 1946-Nov 1946 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Paintings by Jack B. Yeats" Victor Waddington Galleries, Dublin, Feb 1955 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "A Small Collection of Later Work of Jack B. Yeats," The Contemporary Picture Gallery, Dublin, Oct 27, 1941-Nov 8, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Catalog and Invitation: "Paintings by Jack B. Yeats" Wildenstein and Co., Ltd. Gallery, London, Feb 13, 1946-Mar 9, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Invitations: Cuala Press, circa 1940-1950 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Invitation: Jack B. Yeats to Ernie O'Malley and wife to private viewing of exhibition of later paintings, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Invitations to performances of "A Night at the Inn" and "La La Noo" at Abbey Theatre (plays), Apr 1942-May 1942 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1904-1952 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Notebook: Sketches and critiques of paintings in Yeats National Loan Exhibition, Jun 1945; cuid36772 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    This notebook contains a total of 65 pages, only 26 of which have writing.
  - Paintings: reproductions of, from publications, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Photograph: photocopy of reproduction of Thomas MacGreevy at Yeats Exhibit, circa 1947 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Publication: The Dublin Magazine volume 1, number 6, Jan 1924 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Publication: The Dublin Magazine volume 1, number 8, Mar 1924 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Publication: The Treasure of the Garden play by Jack B. Yeats (published by Elkin Mathews, London), undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Yeats, John B.: Essays, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Yeats, John B.: Essays, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Yeats Paintings in Ireland: Lists by Ernie O'Malley, circa 1945 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Yeats Paintings: List by Ernie O'Malley, circa 1945 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Yeats Paintings: Sales history, circa 1945 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Series X. Diaries, Notes and Research, 1922-1963
  The series is arranged chronologically, with Notes arranged alphabetically by subject and filed at the end of the series.
  This series contains diaries, journals, notebooks, loose notes and research by Ernie O'Malley contextualizing his literary output and body of work. Items in this series reflect the commentary, criticisms, critiques and general notes taken by O'Malley on a variety of topics including art, literature, poetry and history, and provide insight into his research methodology and writing process. Most notebooks in this series are untitled, however, some notebooks bear the letters "P" indicating painting, or "I" for Ireland. Of special interest in this series are O'Malley's diaries from his travels in the United States and Mexico, as well as, notebooks relating to his military career. See the accompanying index for an itemized listing, description and full summary of each notebook in this series. Additional notebooks and notes may be found in Series 1: Works and Series 12: Art Materials.
  - Index to Diaries, Notes and Research, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    Diaries, notes and research are arranged chronologically. Diaries and notebooks comprise the first part of the series, arranged by known date and then by items with known date spans. The notes are arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Notebook: reading lists, 1922-1927 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Diary: Europe (I), 1925 (Box 9, Folder 28A)
    Red handwritten diary containing entries while om France and Catalonia during 1925.
  - Diary: Europe (II), 1925 (Box 9, Folder 28B)
  - Diary: Europe (III), 1925 (Box 9, Folder 28C)
  - Diary: Europe (IV), 1925 (Box 9, Folder 28D)
    Notebook containing schedules, itineraries, and diary entries from Ernie O'Malley's visit to Italy.
  - Diary: Europe (VII), 1925 (Box 42, Folder 30)
  - Diary: Pyrenees: I, 1924-1926 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Diary: Pyrenees: II, 1924-1926 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Diary: Pyrenees (handwritten), 1926 (Box 9, Folder 30A)
    Loose handwritten notes from Ernie O'Malley's journey across the south of France to Spain, including notes on the landscape and other landmarks, including the Cathedral of Toulouse.
  - Diary: Pyrenees: typed diary with annotations, 1924-1926 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Notebook: Trip to Italy: I, 1925-1926 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    Notebook concerning Ernie O'Malley's trip to Italy, including illustrations and original writings on Italian art, history, and significant individuals.
  - Notebook: Trip to Italy: II, 1925-1926 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    Notebook concerning Ernie O'Malley's trip to Italy, including writings on the history of and specific landmarks in Rome.
  - Diary: Notes [Italy], 1926 (Box 9, Folder 33A)
  - Diary: Pocket: plays, activities, and places visited, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Diary Fragment: United States, Oct 12-16, 1928; cuid36773 (Box 9, Folder 34A)
    Handwritten diary of Ernie O'Malley's experiences in New York City and California.
    This notebook has 10 pages, all of which are written on.
    Portions of this diary are published in Broken Landscapes: Selected Letters of Ernie O'Malley 1924-1957.
  - Diary: United States (New York), 1928-1929 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Diary, Oct 30-Nov 6, 1928; cuid36774 (Box 9, Folder 35A)
    Diary with handwritten entries from Ernie O'Malley's experiences in Boston; Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; and Cleveland, Ohio.
    This diary has a total of 91 pages, only 32 of which are written on.
  - Notebook: Untitled, Oct-Dec 1928 (Box 9, Folder 35B)
    Notebook containing a list (not written by Ernie O'Malley) of contacts in New York City, in addition to writings by O'Malley about his experiences in the United States.
  - Diary: Irish Press [and other activites in the United States]: I, 1928-1929 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Diary: Irish Press [and other activites in the United States]: II (photocopy), 1928-1929 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Diary: California and New Mexico, untitled, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Diary: California and New Mexico, Sep 11, 1929-Sep 20, 1929; cuid36775 (Box 42, Folder 31)
    This diary contains 67 pages, 65 of which have writing.
  - Diary: California, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 38A)
    Loose diary fragments from Ernie O'Malley's experiences in California.
  - Notes: California, Mar 29-Apr 22, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 38B)
    Loose notes by Ernie O'Malley concerning his experiences in California, including his impressions on food, theatre, and various individuals he met.
  - Notebook: some New Mexico, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    Notebook with original writings by Ernie O'Malley, including journal entries during time period spent in New Mexico and reflections on The Evolution of Sinn Fein: Evidence on Conditions in Ireland.
  - Diary: New Mexico, Sep 1929; cuid36776 (Box 42, Folder 32)
    This diary contains 82 pages, 55 of which have writing.
  - Diary: New Mexico, Sep 1929; cuid36777 (Box 42, Folder 33)
    This diary contains 57 pages, 49 of which have writing.
  - Diary: New Mexico, 1929; cuid36778 (Box 42, Folder 34)
    This diary contains 149 pages, 135 of which have writing.
  - Notebook: New Mexico, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Notebooks: "F", 1930 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    Notebook containing illustrations and writings concerning Ernie O'Malley's experience in Taos, New Mexico, including Irish literature, English literature, and the history and culture of local American Indian tribes.
  - Diary: Mexico, Dec 1930; cuid36779 (Box 42, Folder 35)
    Contains notes on journey from Santa Fe to San Luis Potosi, including illustrations and observations of people, architecture, and sculpture.
    This diary contains 57 pages, 54 of which have writing.
  - Diary: Mexico, Jan 20, 1931-Jan 26, 1931; cuid36780 (Box 42, Folder 36)
    Notebook contains details and observations of daily experiences, people, culture, art, and architecture while in the Cuautla region of Mexico, Mexico City, Yucatan, and Atacomulco.
    This diary contains 88 pages, 83 of which have writing.
  - Diary: Mexico, Jan 26, 1931-Feb 2, 1931; cuid36781 (Box 42, Folder 37)
    Contains daily experiences and illustrations from travels in Mexico, local plant and animal life, observations of people and culture, art, music and scuplture.
    This diary contains 74 pages, 67 of which have writing.
  - Diary: Mexico, Feb 2, 1931-Feb 9, 1931; cuid36782 (Box 42, Folder 38)
    Contains observations of museums visited in Mexico and their holdings, as well as Mexican authors and poets.
    This diary contains 105 pages, 103 of which have writing.
  - Diary: Mexico, Feb 9, 1931-Feb 17, 1931; cuid36783 (Box 42, Folder 39)
    Contains daily experiences, observations on people, culture, art, architecture, and poetry while in Mexico.
    This diary contains 103 pages, 100 of which have writing.
  - Diary: Mexico, Feb 17-26, 1931; cuid36784 (Box 42, Folder 40)
    Contains drawings and observations on experiences in Mexico, including people, culture, domestic architecture, sculpture, and schools.
    This diary contains 117 pages, 113 of which have writing.
  - Diary: Mexico, Feb 27, 1931-Mar 20, 1931; cuid36785 (Box 42, Folder 41)
    Contains drawings and observations from experiences in Mexico, including people, culture, artists, history, lectures attended, and schools.
    This diary contains 216 pages, 174 of which have writing.
  - Diary: Mexico, Mar 21, 1931-Mar 28, 1931; cuid36786 (Box 42, Folder 42)
    Contains drawings, observations, and newspaper clippings from experiences in Mexico, including people, culture, literature, poetry, music, and Mexican pyramids.
    This diary contains 232 pages, 202 of which have writing.
  - Diary: Mexico, 1931; cuid36787 (Box 42, Folder 43)
    This diary contains 37 pages, 26 of which have writing.
  - Diary: Boston and New York, 1933-1935; cuid36788 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    This diary contains a total of 78 pages, 76 of which contain writing.
  - Diary: New York, 1934; cuid36789 (Box 42, Folder 44)
    This diary contains 73 pages, 69 of which have writing.
  - Diary: Various locations: I, 1935-1951 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Diary: Various locations: II (transcript of), 1935-1951 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Diary: Pocket, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Notebook: notes in Ireland, addresses, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    Red leather notebook containing notes on Ireland and lists of Irish towns and counties with early Christian monuments. Notebook also inclues addresses for Liam O'Flaherty, Frank O'Connor, Samuel Beckett, and Dorothy Stuart.
  - Diary: Pocket, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Navy leather pocket diary containing notes, general thoughts, activities, and expenses, in addition to information on payments to Jack B. Yeats for paintings purchased.
  - Notebook: Pocket, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Maroon leather pocket notebook containing addresses; a list of Islands in Clew Bay, Co. Mayo; notes on Irish folklore, in addition to daily notes, lists of songs, and a seating list for a dinner.
  - Notebook: Pocket: Irish folklore, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: Land (the Campanile writing tablet), Jul 1942 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    White notebook containing personal lists, daily journal entries, and research notes on archaeology and Irish folklore.
  - Notebook: Details of Farm at Burrishoole Lodge in Newport, Co. Mayo (bound), 1942-1943 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Maroon notebook with green binding containing information concerning a farm at Burrishoole Lodge in Newport, Co. Mayo, including expenses, management notes, and animal and land usages.
  - Notebook: "No. 3 Farm Accounts Burrishoole Lodge", 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Diary: Pocket, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Diary: "II" [Aran], 1944 (Box 10, Folder 7A)
    Notebook containing autobiographical writings from Ernie O'Malley's visits to the Aran Islands.
  - Diary: "III" [Aran], 1944 (Box 10, Folder 7B)
  - Diary: "IV" [Aran], 1944 (Box 10, Folder 7C)
  - Diary: Boat Trip, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 7D)
    Loose notebook pages containing notes, roughly titled as "Boat trip through Canal."
  - Notebook: "Burrishoole Lodge Farm Book No. 4", Mar 1944-Sep 1944 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Notebook: "Burrishoole Lodge Farm Book No. 5", Sep 1944-Mar 1944 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Notebook: Burrishoole Lodge Farm information; lists of purchases and of books and records (music), 1940-1945 (Box 10, Folder 9A)
  - Notebook: "Anatomy Farm Book No.", 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Diary: Pocket, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Diary: Pocket, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Diary: Partial Entry [Handwritten], 1949 (Box 10, Folder 12A)
  - Notebook: untitled, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 12B)
    Notebook containing lists of names of people, perhaps for potential interviews.
  - Notebook (untitled), Mar 1953-Aug 1953 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Ivory notebook containing personal lists and notes on books made while in St. Brian's Hospital in 1953.
  - Diary: Aran Islands, Aug 1955 (Box 10, Folder 13A)
    Diary containing writings from Ernie O'Malley's visits to Inisheer, the smallest of the Aran Islands.
  - Diary: Aran Islands, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 13B)
    Notebook containing autobiographical writings from Ernie O'Malley's visits to Mexico and the Aran Islands.
  - Notebook (untitled), 1956 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Green, spiral-bound notebook containing addresses and notes and illustrations on France.
  - Notebook, circa 1920-1925 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Black pocket notebook containing notes and instructions (not in Ernie O'Malley's handwriting) on shooting guns.
  - Notebook: "Books and Comments", circa 1923-1924; cuid36790 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Tan notebook containing notes on books read and a chronology of French history.
    This notebook contains 69 pages, 64 of which are written on.
  - Notebook: untitled "A", circa 1926-1928; cuid36791 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Black notebook containing writings on Greek theatre; Italian dramatist Vittorio Alfieri; European literature and poetry, with specific emphasis on works generated in Ireland, Germany, and France; and English poets and authors including Henry Vaughn, Charles Lamb, and Sir Thomas Brown.
    This notebook contains 212 pages, 149 of which have writing.
  - Notebook: untitled "B", circa 1926-1928; cuid36792 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Black notebook containing writings on theatre, acting, playwrights, music, composers, and history. Also included are literary critiques of Francis Thompson, Tom d'Urfey, Heinrich Heine, Daniel Defoe, James Hogg, Francois Rabelais, John Millington Synge, and Oscar Wilde.
    This notebook contains 202 pages, 157 of which have writing.
  - Notebook: untitled "C", circa 1926-1928; cuid36793 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    Black notebook containing lists of winners of the Nobel Prize in Literature, poetry, reflections on classical literature, notes on John Ford, and literary critiques of European and American writers, including Marcel Proust, Matthew Prior, Sir Walter Scott, Jane Austen, Anthony Trollope, and Lord Byron. Notebook also contains original writings concerning Hippocrates, Johann Wolfgang von Goethe, and Luigi Pirandello.
    This notebook contains 202 pages, 168 of which have writing.
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1927 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    Blue, spiral-bound notebook containing poetry by Paul Verlaine, Arthur Rimbaud, Francois Villon, and other French poets.
  - Notebook: "Ireland", circa 1927-1928; cuid36794 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    Tan notebook containing reflections on Irish theatre, music, and law, in addition to critiques and writings on English, Irish, and Anglo-Irish literature, poetry, and authors.
    This notebook contains 196 pages, 130 of which have writing.
  - Notebook: "Painting", circa 1928-1929; cuid36795 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    Brown notebook containing notes from art history books and writings on paintings viewed in museums in Boston, Massachusetts; Cleveland, Ohio; Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; New York; and Washington, D.C.
    This notebook contains 94 pages, 90 of which have writing.
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1928-1929; cuid36796 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    Brown notebook containing writings on paintings viewed in museums in Boston, Massachusetts. Also includes notes on literature, European poetry, and American poetry, with specific emphasis on William Butler Yeats, George Moore, Lady Gregory, John Millington Synge, and Lennox Robinson.
    This notebook contains 101 pages, 89 of which have writing.
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1928-1934; cuid36797 (Box 40, Folder 26)
    Notebook containing research notes concerning Irish history during the 1916-1921 time period, including books read, a chronology of events, and notes from Dail Eireann Minutes.
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1928-1930; cuid36798 (Box 40, Folder 27)
    Notebook containing poems, ballads, book lists, and research notes and original writings concerning Irish history during the 1916-1923 time period.
    This notebook contains 110 pages, 101 of which have writing.
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1928-1934; cuid36799 (Box 40, Folder 28)
    Notebook containing research notes on Irish history, the historical relationship between France and Ireland, American recognition of Czech Slovaks, and the American Committee for Relief in Ireland.
    This notebook contains 204 pages, 144 of which have writing.
  - Notebook: "S", circa 1930-1935 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    Brown notebook containing notes and drafts of descriptions of nature and seasonal weather in Ireland for use in On Another Man's Wound.